<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Matthew J. Oldach</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Matthew J. Oldach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TensorFlow CNN for Fast Style Transfer</title>
      <link>/post/tensorflow-cnn-for-fast-style-transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tensorflow-cnn-for-fast-style-transfer/</guid>
      <description>Volcom was founded in 1991, it was the first company to combine skateboarding, surfing and snowboarding under one brand from it’s incepetion. I always loved how their aesthethics captured the energy and artistry of board-riding in its purest form.
If you have no idea what I’m talking about here’s some samples from print advertisments and a clip from 2003’s Big Youth Happening which I would say was the ultimate inspiration for this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TensorFlow CNN for Fast Style Transfer</title>
      <link>/post/faststyletransfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/faststyletransfer/</guid>
      <description>Volcom was founded in 1991, it was the first company to combine skateboarding, surfing and snowboarding under one brand from it&amp;rsquo;s incepetion. I always loved how their aesthethics captured the energy and artistry of board-riding in its purest form.
If you have no idea what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about here&amp;rsquo;s some samples from print advertisments and a clip from 2003&amp;rsquo;s Big Youth Happening which I would say was the ultimate inspiration for this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step aside Cron, this is a job for .Rprofile &amp; logfiles!</title>
      <link>/post/rprofile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rprofile/</guid>
      <description>Just as test automation is a critical part of rutheless testing, your goal for any project should be to identify taks that can be automated (and do it!).
There are a number of packages that allow you to schedule R scripts at specific times; two that come to mind are taskscheduleR (for Windows) and cronR (for Unix/Linux). We have cronR setup on RStudio server at work, and it has a nice RStudio addin which allows us to schedule tasks around any complex schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image-grid with Ninjutsu CSS theme in Xaringan</title>
      <link>/post/ninjutsu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ninjutsu/</guid>
      <description>A graduate student in our laboratory recently asked me if it was possible to include more than two images, side-by-side, in Xaringan.
Of course anything is possible, however, most blog posts only touch on the most basic things you can do. With custom CSS you can do whatever you want. I wanted to create an image-grid of a bunch of GIFs so I used the ninjutsu theme to accomplish it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Drake in R</title>
      <link>/post/drake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/drake/</guid>
      <description>Recently I got interested in using the xaringan package for creating HTML based R Markdown documents because I could use the widgetframe package to embed htmlwidgets as responsive iframes (I had created some spinning 3D visulizations with pseudo-coloring I wanted to present interactively).
xaringan, it&amp;rsquo;s a R pacakges for creating slideshows with remark.js through R Markdown.
Around the same time I learnt about Drake (or &amp;ldquo;Data Frames in R for Make&amp;rdquo;) which is an amazing a time-saving reproducible build system for data scientist specifically tailored to R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>